JOHN HEHER

Web Developer

Experienced web developer with a focus on the front-end. I have over a decade of dedicated and quality work, ready to help out wherever needed. I'm adaptable to any environment and have worked with big companies and small startups. Most of my career I've been using React with TypeScript/JavaScript but I also have experience using Node and Express for the back-end.

1-512-656-9798 johnheher@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/johnheher github.com/heher johnheher.com

EXPERIENCE

Sabbatical

Earth (11/2022 - 08/2023)

- With the world opening back up after the pandemic, I decided to put all my stuff in storage and solo travel.
- The goal was to go to every Olympic city I could but I also wanted to see as many overall cities and countries as possible along the way. Ended up going to 29 countries.
- Europe: Netherlands, Belgium, Luxembourg, France, Norway, Sweden, Latvia, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Austria, Italy, Switzerland, Liechtenstein, Bosnia and Herzegovina, United Kingdom, Andorra, Spain, Monaco, San Marino, Vatican City, Greece, Denmark and Faroe Islands, Iceland
- Oceania/Asia: New Zealand, Australia, Indonesia, Singapore
- · Americas: Canada

Senior Web Developer

Disney+, Remote (03/2022 - 11/2022)

- Technologies: React, TypeScript, JavaScript, Jest
- Led project for a new onboarding flow for new users, ensuring seamless design across all geographic regions.
- This was a new way for selecting a Disney+ plan when signing up for the service.
- The flow took in multiple APIs across Disney to show/hide content and functionality based on the region's laws and offerings.
- Translated legacy Disney+ code to modern styling and frameworks, which consisted mostly of rewriting React class components written in JavaScript to functional React written in TypeScript.

Senior Web Developer

Palo Alto Networks, Remote (03/2021 - 03/2022)

- Technologies: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Storybook, Ant Design
- Revamped the dashboard within the company's support portal, enhancing performance and features.
- Rewrote components for efficiency and readability as the legacy dashboard was very slow and hard to update.
- Consolidated common styling and components into a new Storybook library.
- Took designs from in-house designs and wrapped Ant Design components to achieve custom functionality with a consistent look.

Director, Front-end development

PHLUR, Austin, TX (11/2016 - 02/2020)

- Technologies: React, JavaScript, GraphQL, Ruby, HTML, CSS, Storybook
- Solely developed and architected all front-end environments in the company, collaborating with designers for pixel-perfect UI/UX and responsive design.
- This included the website, all emails, and any internal tools used within the company.
- Led a comprehensive migration of the codebase to a separate repo using React and GraphQL while adding new products/categories/payment systems.
- Took a chaotic mix of jQuery within the existing Rails app when I was hired to a system made from shared React components/styling and streamlined ordering functionality.

EXPERIENCE CONT.

Presentation Layer Engineer

Razorfish, Austin, TX (09/2014 - 04/2016)

- · Technologies: Jade, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, Sass, jQuery, Node
- Helped lead the overhaul of a banking system for Citibank, coordinating with professionals across the globe.
- Worked within multiple teams to create a unified customer portal for Citi that could be white-labeled with the styling of their partners to feel like a custom experience.
- Took it upon myself to create a unified codebase to align custom styling and functionality with Fortune 500 partners.
- Realizing the dev teams were repeating CSS code, I worked with the lead designer to create a Sass plugin system that could be used to immensely cut down on the time styling a partner page.

Lead Front-end Developer

Greenling, Austin, TX (03/2013 - 09/2014)

- · Technologies: jQuery, CoffeeScript, JavaScript, Ruby, Sass
- Spearheaded a major rebrand, collaborating with designers to deliver a responsive and efficient user experience.
- Was hired to architect and develop all aspects of the visual and functional redesign of the e-commerce site that also included all changes to marketing and invoice emails.

Senior Web Developer

Traction, San Francisco, CA (10/2011 - 07/2012)

- · Technologies: Ruby, YAML, JavaScript, Photoshop
- Coded and QA-tested marketing emails for Apple ensuring consistency across various devices and browsers.
- Used and developed an in-house Ruby templating system to create emails off Photoshop designs that would be uploaded and sent through Apple's system.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Business Administration (Information Technology & E-Commerce) University of Denver, 2010

SKILLS

Front-end

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, TypeScript, Email templates, ADA compliance

Back-end

Node, Ruby on Rails, Docker

Testing

Jest, Testing Library, Playwright

Databases

GraphQL, PostgreSQL, SQL

Design Tools

Photoshop, Figma, Sketch, Storybook

PERSONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Slapped by Saint/Pope John Paul II.
- Successfully crewed and maintained stern lines in 1,000+ mile journey down the Intracoastal Waterway.
- · Ongoing multi-decade reign as family Turkey Trot champion.